♪If I am gone from this world,
will the dark night collapse?♪
♪If I never return
to guard by your side♪
♪If I seal away our encounter
and erase all trace♪
♪Like endless snow
falling into the deep sea♪
♪This life is but a fleeting illusion,
yet it gave me courage♪
♪Love is a miracle♪
=Spring Over Phoenix Pond=
(Adapted from Qin An'an's
"Spring Over Phoenix Pond")
=Episode 17=
Is it all done?
I saw the tea spill onto her
with my own eyes.
It's colorless and leaves no trace.
Qi Yuan,
because of you, my son was stripped
of his title and rank.
You should have seen this day coming.
I got the Lost-Soul Incense
from Prince Qi.
When you breathe in
the flower's fragrance,
your limbs will go weak,
and you'll lose consciousness.
And you'll be at my mercy.
If she were reciting scriptures,
how could there be no sound at all?
Please reconsider, Your Highness.
Entering the inner palace
without permission is a capital offense.
Why not ask the Crown Princess
to step in?
Mother is in the Eastern Palace.
There isn't time.
If anything happens to Qi Yuan.
Your Highness!
Your Highness,
Prince Jing is here.
This is the inner palace.
I doubt he'd dare intrude.
Come now, beauty.
No one I want
has ever escaped me.
You...
It's you.
What?
Did you think I was dead?
I just didn't expect you
to save me.
Don't flatter yourself.
I have a private grudge
against this beast.
Help me.
Who is there?
How dare you break into
Her Highness's bedchamber?
Open your eyes wide.
(Jing)
This is Prince Jing.
Forgive me, Your Highness.
Consort Little Liu has ordered
that no one may enter today.
Trying to run?
Beast!
Let me go.
Weren't you so fierce just now?
Still trying to act smug in front of me?
I will destroy you anyway.
Prince Jing?
Consort Little Liu has ordered
that no one may enter today.
Move aside.
I will destroy you anyway.
♪Leaves fall in the cold wind,
a fleeting glance between pavilions♪
♪Still unable to step out of this
devout dream until the end of time♪
♪Love drifts through the whirlpool
of farewell, brushing past me♪
♪Only longing
leaves me wounded all over♪
♪Yet I still fear you'll forget me♪
I entered the palace
by imperial decree.
Please spare me, Your Highness.
I can't.
I went to see Prince Qi.
I have no idea
what kind of person I was
in my past life.
But if what Prince Qi said is true,
that I used you to gain a bright future,
then it's only right for you
to hate me.
I didn't know these things before.
I forced you to love me.
But now,
I will never force you even a little.
I'll give you my whole heart
and ask for nothing in return.
If you wish to be with me,
nothing would make me happier.
If not,
I won't blame you.
But I want you to know this
that in this life,
I, Xiao Yunting,
will never hurt you again.
♪To change an uncertain fate,
never part again♪
♪If I seal away our encounter
and erase all trace♪
♪Like endless snow
falling into the deep sea♪
♪This life is but a fleeting illusion♪
You're fine now.
I'll take you home.
♪Love is a miracle♪
Prince Jing,
how dare you break into the inner palace.
This is a capital offense.
Are you not afraid
His Majesty will hold you accountable?
Your Highness,
don't be so quick to accuse.
Why don't you explain
why Miss Qi, who entered the palace
by imperial decree,
ended up being drugged in your palace?
How insolent!
The inner palace is a forbidden ground.
Where would any drug come from?
Your Highness, we've checked.
Prince Cheng is not in the palace.
No one saw him come or go.
The drug leaves no trace.
They have no evidence.
I'm dizzy right now.
I need to go outside and get some air.
Stop right there.
Since you insist on leaving,
I'll grant your wish.
As for the charge of trespassing,
I've warned you.
Your Majesty,
Prince Jing defied palace rules
and broke into Siliu Pavilion.
You must stand up for me.
Xiao Yunting,
do you know
you have committed a capital crime?
I'm willing to die.
But please let me finish speaking.
At noon today,
Miss Qi Yuan
of the Marquis Yongping Residence
was to meet me outside Donghua Gate,
but she never arrived.
I was worried for her safety,
which is why I broke into Siliu Pavilion.
But when I arrived,
Miss Qi had already been drugged
and was unconscious.
If I had been a moment later,
the consequences
would have been disastrous.
Drugged?
Your Majesty,
it's impossible
for something so vile
to be found in Siliu Pavilion.
I beg Your Majesty
to investigate at once.
If there's no evidence,
please deal with this
according to palace law.
If no solid proof is found,
I'm willing to take my own life
to set the record straight.
(Tower of Remembrance)
How could this have happened?
Your Majesty,
when I found Miss Qi,
she was injured near here.
If I had been any later,
she might have lost her life.
Your Highness.
Prince Cheng has a knife wound.
If his body is found,
it would inevitably
be traced back.
Consort Little Liu,
why are there so many buried bones
in the inner palace?
What is going on here?
I beg you to judge this fairly.
I know nothing about this.
It was her.
She must've done this behind my back.
Your Highness,
you ordered me to...
You insolent servant!
How dare you falsely accuse me?
That's enough.
Consort Little Liu,
you have disappointed me.
Draft the decree.
Consort Little Liu has allowed
her servants to commit murder.
She is to be demoted to concubine rank
and confined for three months.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty...
Prince Jing broke into the inner palace.
Though it was to save someone,
his conduct was reckless.
Punish him with twenty lashes
as a warning.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
♪How I wish to hold onto
this fleeting warmth♪
♪How I wish to live this life
only for you♪
♪When memories sink
and the heart settles♪
♪Forgetting life, death,
parting, and reunion♪
♪How I wish to stay
only in the moment with you♪
♪Anchoring myself by your side♪